在上一集里
Previously on Transformers: Prime
干得漂亮 擎天柱！
Bravo, Optimus!
你最好为正戏保存一点实力！
You may wish to save your strength for the main event!
我们得找到福勒 再把孩子们带出去
We need to find Fowler and get these kids outta here.
我们被卷进来 都是因为你
It's your fault that we're stuck in this intensity.
你是怎么想的 神子？
What were you thinking, Miko?
我一看就知道那是数学问题
I know math when I see it.
那可是个信息量巨大的方程式
And that is one serious equation.
如果和汽车人在一起 每天都有生命危险
If this was just an average day with the Autobots
那我不干了
then I don't wanna be a part of it.
可你干的蠢事弄垮了我的飞船！
Your mindless agenda resulted in the disabling of my ship!
还耽误了我的大事！
And the delay of my plans!
威震天正在建造太空桥
Megatron's building a Space Bridge
用它召集一支征服大军
to bring through his conquering army.
可是 唯一能让威震天召唤无数死人的地方是…
But the only place Megatron could recruit that many fallen warriors...
塞博特恩
Cybertron.
绝不能让威震天用他的太空桥传送黑暗能量
We cannot allow Megatron to send Dark Energon through his Space Bridge.
如果我们失败了
If we fail
塞博特恩的死者们将会复活
the dead of Cybertron will rise
冲破他的时空漩涡
swarm through his vortex
并侵略地球
and invade Earth
人类将在威震天的邪恶统治下痛不欲生
bending human kind to Megatron's twisted rule.
单车不错嘛
Nice bike.
阿尔茜 说真的 神子已经和我谈过了
Arcee, really, Miko already tried.
告诉擎天柱 我非常敬重他 但…
Tell Optimus I respect him big time. But...
如果你们跟霸天虎交战的话
if you're at war with the Decepticons
我也帮不上什么忙
there's nothing I can do to help.
不是擎天柱派我来的 也没人请你帮忙
Optimus didn't send me, and no one's asking for your help.
好吧 既然你我都知道 我不是打仗的料…
Ok, so if we both agree that I'm not warrior material...
杰克 我刚失去了一个知心朋友
Jack, I just lost someone I cared about.
可能是出于悲痛…
Maybe it's the grief talking...
也可能是和你投缘
maybe you're growing on me.
无论怎样 我还不想说再见
Whatever it is, I'm just not ready to say good-bye.
擎天柱 我找到威震天那个太空桥的方位了
Optimus, I've pinpointed the location of Megatron's Space Bridge.
在地球轨道的最高点上
High in Earth's orbit.
超出了我们的行动范围
Out of our reach.
好吧 就算你们不能飞
Ok, so you guys don't fly.
那么用环陆桥不就行了吗？
But can't you just Ground Bridge there?
环陆桥的传输范围是有限的
A Ground Bridge has limited range.
冲进环轨道运行的时空漩涡
Stretch all the way into the orbited vortex could snap
可能会把我们弹射到宇宙的任何地方
and scatter us to the stars.
威震天应该已经在招兵买马了
Since Megatron is likely already in transit
恐怕我们要硬闯虎穴
I'm afraid we must take that risk.
要想制止他 我们只有到太空桥上殊死一搏了
Reaching the Space Bridge first, is our only means of stopping him.
嘿 猜猜谁回来了
Hey, guess who's back.
汽车人 准备出发
Autobots, prepare for departure.
去哪儿？
Where to?
“最后的边疆”（《星际迷航》台词）
The final frontier.
太空？我还以为他们没法上天呢
Space? I... I thought they didn't have any way to get there.
他们不能
They don't
的确不能
really.
那就回头见了？
Umm, be seeing you?
小心点儿 大黄蜂
Be careful, Bee.
我真是眼红
I'm so jealous.
甭想找借口跟着我
Don't even think about following me.
擎天柱 如果你把我永远丢在这个只有人类的星球上
Optimus, if you leave me stranded on a planet teeming with humans
我决不会原谅你
I will never forgive you.
后会有期 老朋友
Until we meet again, old friend.
汽车人 出发！
Autobots, roll out!
全速前进！
Maximum overdrive!
汽车人 变形！
Autobots, transform
着陆！
and gravitise!
别往下看 别往上看 别往左看
Don't look down, or up, or left.
这么说 威震天准备了足够的黑暗能量 足以让塞博特恩的死者全都复活？
So Megatron's packing enough Dark Energon to raise Cybertron's dead?
既然我们没有十足的把握关闭太空桥
And since we don't possess ready means of disabling the Space Bridge
那就谁也休想从这儿进出！
nothing gets in or out.
擎天柱从来不会让人失望
Hahaha... Optimus Prime never disappoints.
不像你 红蜘蛛！
Unlike you, Starscream!
不必担心 主人
No need for concern, master.
声波正在锁定塞博特恩的坐标
Soundwave is locking on to Cybertron's coordinates
是我让他去做的
per my instructions.
那个…他们还在等什么？
Well, what are they waiting for?
看来霸天虎飞船的星际导航系统出现了严重的损坏
It appears that the Decepticons have sustained serious damage to their inter-stellar navigation system.
噢 那是我干的
Oh, that's my handy work.
做得好 隔板
Great job, Bulkhead.
没有天线
Without the dish
威震天就无法让太空桥和塞博特恩对接
Megatron will be unable to aim the Space Bridge at Cybertron.
霸天虎连自己的星球都找不到吗？
Don't the Decepticons know where their own planet is?
当然能
Naturally
但塞博特恩位于数万光年以外
but Cybertron is many light years away.
要想连接目的地 他们的定位必须无比精准
To reach their target, their aim must be astronomically precise.
如果威震天在和太空桥接轨时出了问题
If Megatron went to the trouble of rendezvousing with his Space Bridge
他必然会借助于另一个定位系统
He must have an alternate targeting system.
一个远距离系统
A remote one.
哼 根据我对地球科技的了解
From what I know of Earth technology
这个星球上没有一个射电望远镜天线
I doubt there would exist a single radio telescope dish on this planet
功率大到可以锁定塞博特恩
powerful enough to pinpoint Cybertron.
如果用射电望远镜天线阵列呢
What about a whole bunch of linked radio telescope dishes?
比如说德克萨斯州的那个阵列？
Like the giant size array in Texas?
老实呆着…这可不是在过家家
Sit back... this is not a child's play.
好主意 拉夫
Good thinking, Raf.
救护车 让福勒探员通知阵列的工作人员 提高警惕
Ratchet, have Agent Fowler alert the array's stuff to the security hazard.
你 大兵！
You, soldier
你没穿制服 把裤子穿上！
you're out of uniform. Put on some pants.
这恐怕难度不小
That maybe a challenge.
我没法入侵阵列的防火墙
I can't get passed the array's firewalls.
安全系数太高了
They're too thick.
你…以为自己能挡得住那些霸天虎吗？
You... actually think you could keep the Decepticons out?
只要能…入侵系统的话…
Maybe... if I could get in.
等等 拉夫
Wait, wait, wait. Raf.
我们把你送到…最里边怎么样？\N也就是说“建筑内部”？
What if we could get you... all the way in? Like "inside the building" in?
我可以在防火墙的另一端登录他们的内部网络
I can login to their internal network on the other side of the firewall.
这样太冒险了
The risk is too great.
霸天虎也会去那儿的 很可能现在就到了
The Decepticons will be there. Perhaps even on site.
擎天柱 恕我直言
Optimus, with all due respect
你自己说过
you said that yourself
这远比三个地球人的安危更重要
this is bigger than the safety of three humans.
是啊 如果让虎子们赢了
Yeah, if we let the Cons win
我们会和地球上所有的人一起遭殃
we're fragged along with everyone else on our planet.
拉夫？
Raf?
我想试试看
I want to give it a shot.
我敢肯定 威震天陛下
Surely, Lord Megatron
汽车人想搞破坏
the Autobots are up to something.
真的吗 红蜘蛛？
Really, Starscream?
干掉他们！
Crush them!
大队人马前来迎驾了
Here comes the welcoming committee.
- 还得适应一阵子\N- 喔…
- That'll take some getting used to.\N - Wow...
这里的安全系统太差劲了
Security sure is lack in this place.
我进入系统了…
I'm in...
可这好像是霸天虎的系统
and so are the Decepticons.
什么？
What?
你怎么知道？
How can you tell?
看这些图表 外星方程式和他们船上的一样
Schematics, with the same alien math we saw on their ship.
但这次 我能下载了
But this time, I can download it.
一定是太空桥
It's got to be the Space Bridge.
霸天虎在把它和天线同步
The Decepticons are synching it to the dishes.
但我也能如法炮制
But I can synch to them.
他们会发现吗？
Will they know?
就算霸天虎发现我入侵了系统
Even if the Decepticons see that I'm in the system
也想不到我就在这间屋子里
they'll have no idea I'm in the house.
这是怎么回事？
What just happened?
霸天虎正在锁定塞博特恩
The Decepticons are locking on to Cybertron.
威震天陛下 太空桥随时可以启动
Lord Megatron, the Space Bridge is ready for activation.
总算好了！
Finally!
他们要锁定塞博特恩 别高兴得太早
They're locked on to Cybertron, but not for long.
没错 大黄蜂
Indeed, Bumblebee
这一定是拉夫干的
this can only be Raf's doing.
红蜘蛛！什么情况？
Starscream, what is happening?
声波！什么情况？
Soundwave, what is happening?
天线又转向塞博特恩了
The dishes are heading back towards Cybertron.
我让它们再转回来
I'll just undo that again.
万一虎子们知道被耍了 怎么办？
What happens when the Cons realize to being punked?
这只是虚拟战斗
It's only virtual combat.
就像在线游戏一样
You know, like online gaming.
是啊 杰克 虎子们还能怎么办？
Yeah, Jack, what are the Cons gonna do?
他们很可能远在千里之外呢
They're probably like a thousand miles away.
我不会再让他们锁定了
I won't let them lock on again.
你送给他一把斧头？！
You handed in an axe?!
惨了！
Not good.
他怎么走了？
Why's he leaving?
他把主线切断了
He cut the hard line.
天线已经被锁定在塞博特恩了…
The dishes are locked on to Cybertron...
永久地
for good.
开始吧 红蜘蛛
Now, Starscream.
开始
Now.
最后一搏！
At last!
觉醒吧 我的军团！
Arise, my legion!
那个…我们如何击败整个星球的活死人？
So, how do we beat a whole planet of the undead?
擎天柱
Optimus
他们的太空桥漩涡里出现一股能量 而且在迅速增强
I'm registering a rapidly expanding mass in their Space Bridge vortex
能量特征非常诡异
one with a peculiar energy signature.
黑暗能量
Dark Energon.
救护车 我们必须摧毁太空桥
Ratchet, we must destroy the Space Bridge.
现在通过漩涡的生命能量足够多 可以实施爆破
There's enough live energon coursing through it, to achieve detonation.
但我们的火力还不足以引爆它
But we lack the fire power to ignite it.
如果我知道太空桥的工程原理
If I knew how the Space Bridge was engineered
也许能从技术上找到突破口
I might find a technical way of accomplishing at feet.
呃 用图表可以吗？
Umm, will schematics help?
擎天柱 我必须提醒你
Optimus, I must say
太空桥是我们返回塞博特恩的唯一希望
the Space Bridge is our sole hope of ever returning to Cybertron.
你确定摧毁它是唯一的选择吗？
Are you certain its destruction is the only option?
恐怕是的
I am afraid so.
那就全力以赴吧
Then by all means
让我们照亮这最黑暗的时刻吧！
let us light our darkest hour!
汽车人 各就各位
Autobots, take your positions
听救护车指挥
and follow Ratchet's lead.
这里就交给我了
While I make my stand.
你的汽车人伙伴还算识时务 擎天柱
Your fellow Autobots are wise, Optimus.
他们知道什么时候应该撤退
They know when to retreat.
我没打算跟你整支军团硬拼 威震天
I hold no illusions about engaging your army, Megatron.
但我会让他们溃不成军…
But I might derail its objective...
我要擒贼先擒王！
by removing its head.
完全赞同 擎天柱
Highly and likely Optimus
因为强大的力量已集我于一身！
as I am infused with their very might!
不是你死 就是我亡！
One shall stand, one shall fall!
那些东西越来越近了
These things are getting closer.
情况不妙 对吧？
That's bad, right?
救护车 我们已经就位
Ratchet, we're in position.
阿尔茜 仔细看好
Arcee, pay close attention.
主人？
Master?
红蜘蛛 又怎么了？
Starscream, what is it?!
我不想质疑您运筹帷幄的智慧
I do not wish to question your all-seeing wisdom
但我认为 汽车人又在捣鬼
but I believe the Autobots are up to something again.
这次是在您的桥下
Beneath your bridge, this time.
声东击西啊 擎天柱
Uh, misdirection, Optimus?
你做霸天虎一定出类拔萃！
You would have made a fine Decepticon!
我已经选择了阵营！
I chose my side!
红蜘蛛 我的军队已经接近了
Starscream, my army approaches.
到太空桥会合 准备接应！
Rendezvous with the Space Bridge for pickup!
沿着流量调节器的线路走到能量泵
Now follow the line from the flow regulator to the energon pump.
那里应该有个阀门
There should be a valve.
我看到了
I see it.
好 让它用自己的能量进行爆破
Good. To turn all that power against itself
你只需要改变电流的方向
all you need do is reverse the current.
电流转向完成
Current reversed.
太好了！
Yes!
没错吧？
Right?
我去准备环陆桥
I'll ready the Ground Bridge.
红蜘蛛！我的飞船在哪儿？
Starscream! Where is my ship?
我们顶不住了 威震天陛下
We would never make it, Lord Megatron!
别犯傻了 上船撤退吧！
Don't be a fool! Take flight and retreat!
擎天柱 环陆桥已经准备就绪！
Optimus, the Ground Bridge is ready and waiting!
汽车人 跳桥！
Autobots, jump!
我的军团啊…
My legion!
不！
No!
霸天虎们 我怀着沉痛的心情
Decepticons, it is with deep sorrow
向大家宣告…
that I note for the log...
威震天的火种已经熄灭了
Megatron's spark has been extinguished.
红蜘蛛…万…岁！
All... hail... Starscream!
你觉得…他们…
Do you... think they're...
四个生命信号
Four life signals.
有一个非常微弱
One very faint.
隔板！
Bulkhead!
这周我们已经失去了一个
We lost one this week
看在火种源的份上 别再上演悲剧了
by the Allspark, don't let it be two.
阿尔茜…
Arcee...
杰克 不用伤心吧？
Jack, really?
世界上有的是摩托车
There are other motorcycles in the world.
可你是我的第一辆
But you're my first.
威震天怎么了？
And Megatron?
就算他也绝不可能在爆炸中心幸存
Not even he could've survived Ground Zero.
擎天柱！
Prime!
我还没谢过你 但你们救了我
I didn't get to thank you, but for the save
算我欠你的
I owe you one.
全人类欠你们的
We all do.
那么 现在是不是该说再见了
So, is this the part where you say good-bye
要我们忘记曾经见过你们吗？
and tell us we need to forget we ever saw you?
现在我们已经无法离开这个世界了
Without the means of leaving this world
但汽车人与三个年轻的朋友建立了友谊\N并从中得到力量
we Autobots take strength in the bonds we have forged with our three young friends.
他们是真正的勇士
True warriors
虽然身体弱小
if not in body
但拥有坚强的意志
then in spirit.
我的名字是擎天柱
My name is Optimus Prime.
我发出这条信息：
And I send this message:
虽然留在地球并非我们所选
Though we did no choose to be of earth
但既来之 则安之
it would seem that we are here to stay.
如果有人怀着敌意前来进犯
If you approach this planet with hostile intent
请记住：
know this:
我们会保卫自己
we will defend ourselves
我们会保卫人类
we will defend humanity.
我们会保卫我们共同的家园
We will defend our home.